<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writings on Pavel Rudnev’s website</title>
    <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writings on Pavel Rudnev’s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linearisation constraints on sentential negation in Russian Sign Language are prosodic</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/sll-squib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/sll-squib/</guid>
      <description>This short remark documents exceptions to the main strategy of expressing sentential negation in Russian Sign Language (RSL). The postverbal sentential negation particle in RSL inverts the basic SVO order characteristic of the language turning it into SOV. We show that this reversal requirement under negation is not absolute and does not apply to prosodically heavy object NPs. The resulting picture accords well with the view of RSL word order laid out by Kimmelman (2012) and supports a model of grammar where syntactic computation has access to phonological information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Against Upwards Agree</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/against-ua/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/against-ua/</guid>
      <description>Bjorkman &amp;amp; Zeijlstra (2019) claim that agreement with the absolutive argument in ergative-absolutive languages follows naturally in an Upwards-Agree system supplemented by the relation of Accessibility if φ-agreement is parasitic on structural case assigned to the absolutive noun phrase either by T° or by v°. By drawing evidence from two distantly related East Caucasian languages—Chirag and Avar—the present article argues that this theory is both too strong and too weak. I then show that the problematical facts are trivially analysable with standard Agree (Chomsky 2000 et seq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agreeing adpositions in Avar and the directionality of valuation debate</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/agreeing-adpositions-in-avar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/agreeing-adpositions-in-avar/</guid>
      <description>Given the central spot afforded to unvalued features in current theorizing, the directionality of feature valuation is the subject of a lively debate in the syntactic literature. The traditional conception of upward valuation, whereby the unvalued probe inherits features from a valued goal in its c-command domain (Chomsky 2000, 2001a, Carstens 2013, Preminger 2013), has to compete with downward valuation (Zeijlstra 2012), Hybrid Agree (Bjorkman &amp;amp; Zeijlstra 2018), bidirectional Agree (Baker 2008), amongst others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not all obligatory control is movement</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/oblique-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/oblique-control/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents two challenges for the analysis of promise-type verbs within the Movement Theory of Control. We show that the objects of these verbs in Russian are not prepositional and are incorrectly predicted to be legitimate controllers. We also argue, based on the patterns of polarity licensing, scope licensing and case marking on floating quantifiers, against analysing oblique control as sidewards movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case marking in Russian eventive nominalisations revisited</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/russian-nominalisations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/russian-nominalisations/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we analyse case marking in Russian eventive nominalisations recently discussed in Pereltsvaig 2018 with regards to two competing theories of case: the Inherent Case Theory (Woolford 2006; 2009) and the Dependent Case Theory (Marantz 1991). We contest the view that Russian eventive nominalisations display ergative alignment (Koptjevskaja-Tamm 1993) and argue that Russian is a nominative-accusative language across the board. We propose an analysis for the syntax of Russian eventive nominalisations and show that, contrary to Pereltsvaig (2018), they are in principle incapable of disproving the DCT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Anaphor Agreement Effect is not about featural deficiency: Evidence from Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/aae-squib/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/aae-squib/</guid>
      <description>This paper discusses two analyses of the Anaphor Agreement Effect (AAE, Rizzi 1990) in the light of novel data from Avar. By demonstrating that Avar anaphors trigger full, non-trivial agreement on the ϕ-probe, I argue that the Avar data instantiate a genuine exception to the AAE. I then compare two competing analyses of binding and the AAE: an account whereby anaphoric dependencies arise via the syntactic operation Agree (Murugesan 2018), and a theory deriving the inability of the anaphors’ ϕ-features to trigger full agreement from the presence of additional structural layers inside the anaphors that render the features inaccessible (Preminger 2019).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic detection of natural phonological classes in Russian Sign Language</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/rsl-phonology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/rsl-phonology/</guid>
      <description>The present paper applies Multiple Correspondence Analysis to test the validity of an existing theoretical model of the phonological system of Russian Sign Language (RSL). We show that comparing the importance of phonological features using ratio plots and MCA is a promising way of revealing non-binary oppositions in phonological systems of human languages irrespective of modality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some difficulties deriving the positive polarity behaviour of plain disjunction in Russian: Remarks on Nicolae 2017</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/ppi-disjunctions-in-russian-squib/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/ppi-disjunctions-in-russian-squib/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Nicolae (2017) develops an account of PPI-disjunctions whereby the unacceptability of plain disjunction in DE-environments results from an economy condition imposed on obligatory exhaustification. This remark shows this general mechanism to be insufficient to account for the behaviour of the Russian plain disjunction marker ili, whose scope properties are argued to correlate with the phrasal vs. clausal nature of the disjunction: phrasal disjunction yields narrow scope whilst clausal disjunction yields wide scope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimal pronouns, logophoricity, and long-distance reflexivisation in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/minimal-pronouns-logophoricity-avar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/minimal-pronouns-logophoricity-avar/</guid>
      <description>This paper discusses two morphologically related anaphoric pronouns in Avar (Avar-Andic, Nakh-Daghestanian) and proposes that one of them should be treated as a minimal pronoun that receives its interpretation from a λ-operator situated on a phasal head whereas the other is a logophoric pronoun denoting the author of the reported event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Events, locations and situations: On the interaction of negation and finiteness in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/events-locations-and-situations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/events-locations-and-situations/</guid>
      <description>This paper documents a number of restrictions on negation marking in Avar, a Northeast Caucasian language, and presents a tentative analysis of the observed morphosyntactic facts as having a semantic basis. The two different negation markers are analysed, based on the proposal in (Ramchand &amp;amp; Svenonius 2014), as taking complements of a different semantic type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>_Kendisi_ revisited</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/kendisi-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/kendisi-revisited/</guid>
      <description>The present contribution follows up on Rudnev 2011, which, in turn, was based on a presentation I gave in Barbara Partee&amp;rsquo;s semantics class in the spring of 2008. It is for this reason that I omit most of the arguments for the pronominal nature of kendisi and present a formalisation of its semantic properties based on Partee 1983 and Elbourne 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependency and discourse-configurationality</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/dependency-and-discourse-configurationality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/dependency-and-discourse-configurationality/</guid>
      <description>The present thesis provides a detailed description of the syntactic and semantic properties of a number of related constructions in Avar, a Northeast Caucasian language. These include relativisation, wh-questions and focus sentences, all of which are created via a dependency between an abstract operator and a variable. In addition to the description a generative analysis is developed whereby the relative clause is treated as the structural core for the remaining constructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the coreference rule: Reflexivity in Russian Sign Language</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/breaking-coreference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/breaking-coreference/</guid>
      <description>This paper is concerned with the distribution of reflexive and non-reflexive pronouns in local anaphoric configurations in (three dialects of) Russian Sign Language (RSL). We demonstrate that most of the observed facts can be accounted for on a Binding Theory supplemented by a version of the Coreference Rule (Büring 2005). We also show that an additional mechanism, coreference via the signing space, is required to explain certain cases of non-complementarity. A related mechanism is proposed to account for similar facts in spoken languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Рефлексивы в дагестанских языках и природа анафорических отношений</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/refleksivy-v-dagestanskix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/refleksivy-v-dagestanskix/</guid>
      <description>In this paper I discuss the data from North-East Caucasian languages from the perspective of current views on the syntax and semantics of anaphora.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Turkish _kendisi_ is a pronominal</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/why-kendisi-is-a-pronominal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/why-kendisi-is-a-pronominal/</guid>
      <description>This paper is concerned with the syntax and semantics of the Turkish pronominal element kendisi ‘self.3SG’ that has so far received very little attention in the literature on anaphoric relations. We start out by examining the properties of this pronoun proceeding next to discuss the few existing proposals highlighting their inadequacies when confronted with novel data. We argue that despite its reflexive root, kendisi should be treated as a pronominal for the purposes of the Binding Theory, and should be sensitive to Condition B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Hicks, Glyn. 2009. _The derivation of anaphoric relations_. John Benjamins: Amsterdam/Philadelphia</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/osla-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/osla-review/</guid>
      <description>This paper reviews the derivational approach to binding as proposed by Glyn Hicks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>