<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" 
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
  xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">

<channel>
      <title>Pavel Rudnev’s website in Pavel Rudnev’s website </title>
	  <itunes:subtitle>Greg Restall's publications on logic and philosophy</itunes:subtitle>
	  <itunes:author>Greg Restall</itunes:author>
	  <itunes:owner>
	  <itunes:name>Greg Restall</itunes:name>
	  <itunes:email>greg@consequently.org</itunes:email>
	  </itunes:owner>
	  <itunes:category text="Education">
	  <itunes:category text="Higher Education"/>
	  </itunes:category>
	  <itunes:keywords>Philosophy, Logic, mathematics, pdf, research, University, Greg Restall, Melbourne, Australia, Victoria</itunes:keywords>
	  <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
	  <itunes:image href="https://pavelrudnev.github.io/img/avatar2.jpg" />
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 13:50:45 MSK</updated>


<item>
<title>Writings</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/</guid>
<description></description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Pavel Rudnev’s website</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/</guid>
<description></description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Agreeing adpositions in Avar and the directionality of valuation debate</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/agreeing-adpositions-in-avar/</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/agreeing-adpositions-in-avar/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the central spot afforded to unvalued features in current theorizing, the directionality of feature valuation is the subject of a lively debate in the syntactic literature. The traditional conception of upward valuation, whereby the unvalued probe inherits features from a valued goal in its c-command domain (Chomsky 2000, 2001a, Carstens 2013, Preminger 2013), has to compete with downward valuation (Zeijlstra 2012),  Hybrid Agree (Bjorkman &amp;amp; Zeijlstra 2018), bidirectional Agree (Baker 2008), amongst others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The present paper discusses, using data from Avar, a crosslinguistically rare phenomenon of adposition agreement, whereby certain adverbs, postpositions and locative case forms undergo agreement with an absolutive argument.  I show that the agreement morphology on agreeing adpositions is a result of agreement rather than concord and explore the consequences of adposition agreement in Avar for upward and downward valuation. I conclude that upward valuation is better equipped to account for the observed patterns than downward valuation, both on empirical and conceptual grounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the author&amp;rsquo;s final version of an article accepted to appear in &lt;em&gt;Linguistic Inquiry&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Not all obligatory control is movement</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/oblique-control/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/oblique-control/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This paper presents two challenges for the analysis of &lt;em&gt;promise&lt;/em&gt;-type verbs within the Movement Theory of Control. We show that the objects of these verbs in Russian are not prepositional and are incorrectly predicted to be legitimate controllers. We also argue, based on the patterns of polarity licensing, scope licensing and case marking on floating quantifiers, against analysing oblique control as sidewards movement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>The Anaphor Agreement Effect is not about featural deficiency: Evidence from Avar</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/aae-squib/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/aae-squib/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This paper discusses two analyses of the Anaphor Agreement Effect (AAE, Rizzi 1990) in the light of novel data from Avar. By demonstrating that Avar anaphors trigger full, non-trivial agreement on the ϕ-probe, I argue that the Avar data instantiate a genuine exception to the AAE. I then compare two competing analyses of binding and the AAE: an account whereby anaphoric dependencies arise via the syntactic operation Agree (Murugesan 2018), and a theory deriving the inability of the anaphors’ ϕ-features to trigger full agreement from the presence of additional structural layers inside the anaphors that render the features inaccessible (Preminger 2019). I claim that the absence of the AAE in Avar supports the encapsulation analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Case marking in Russian eventive nominalisations revisited</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/russian-nominalisations/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/russian-nominalisations/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we analyse case marking in Russian eventive nominalisations recently discussed in Pereltsvaig 2018 with regards to two competing theories of case: the Inherent Case Theory (Woolford 2006; 2009) and the Dependent Case Theory (Marantz 1991). We contest the view that Russian eventive nominalisations display ergative alignment (Koptjevskaja-Tamm 1993) and argue that Russian is a nominative-accusative language across the board. We propose an analysis for the syntax of Russian eventive nominalisations and show that, contrary to Pereltsvaig (2018), they are in principle incapable of disproving the DCT. The resulting analysis is trivially compatible with the DCT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Presentations</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/</guid>
<description></description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Dynamic locality, split ergativity and adposition agreement in Avar</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/iatl-2019/</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/iatl-2019/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: In this talk, I develop a configurational approach to case and agreement in the Avar biabsolutive constructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a peer-reviewed talk, for the 35th annual meeting of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iatl.org.il/?page_id=1646&#34;&gt;Israel Association for Theoretical Linguistics&lt;/a&gt;, at The Open University in Ra&amp;rsquo;anana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can view the slides &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavelrudnev.github.io/papers/iatl-35-spellout.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Dynamic locality, split ergativity and adposition agreement in Avar</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/lagb2019/</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/lagb2019/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: In this talk, I develop a configurational approach to case and agreement in the Avar biabsolutive constructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a peer-reviewed talk, for the 2019 Annual Meeting of the Linguistics Association of Great Britain at Queen Mary University of London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can view the slides &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavelrudnev.github.io/papers/lagb2019-slides.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Dynamic phases, split ergativity and adposition agreement in Avar</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/camcos8/</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/camcos8/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: In this talk, I develop a configurational approach to case and agreement in the Avar biabsolutive constructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a peer-reviewed talk, for the 8th installment of Cambridge Comparative Syntax at St John&amp;rsquo;s College, Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can view the slides &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavelrudnev.github.io/papers/camcos8-slides.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>News</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/</guid>
<description></description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Talks at CamCoS 8 and SLE 52</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2019/camcos8/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2019/camcos8/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In the spring/summer of 2019, I will give peer-reviewed talks at the eighth installment of the Cambridge Comparative Syntax conference (CamCoS) at the University of Cambridge and the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Societas Linguistica Europæa in Leipzig.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Towards an exhaustification analysis of plain disjunction in Russian</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/farl3/</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/farl3/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It has been known since at least Szabolcsi 2002 that the Russian plain disjunction marker &lt;em&gt;ili&lt;/em&gt; behaves as a positive polarity item (PPI) when occurring under clausemate negation, which manifests itself in a violation of De Morgan’s laws. Among properties which the Russian plain disjunction marker &lt;em&gt;ili&lt;/em&gt; shares with conventional PPIs such as
&lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; are the locality of anti-licensing and the ability to be rescued by a second negation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Russian plain disjunction marker &lt;em&gt;ili&lt;/em&gt; displays variable behaviour with respect to PPI-hood when interacting with Ā-movement. When the disjunction phrase appears to the left of the sentential negation marker &lt;em&gt;ne&lt;/em&gt; ‘not’, the narrow-scope reading is strongly preferred. Exhaustification-based analyses of scalar inferences (Chierchia, Fox &amp;amp; Spector 2012, Spector 2014, Nicolae 2017) derive the basic pattern effortlessly but struggle with accounting for the observed obviation effects under syntactic fronting, as it is not clear if the account should be semantic or syntactic. Potential arguments for the syntactic approach would be the involvement of syntactic movement and the plausibility of the sentential negation marker &lt;em&gt;ne&lt;/em&gt; being merely a negative concord item/NPI rather than the fully-fledged negation (Zeijlstra 2004). On this view, moving the disjunction phrase past the negation marker and closer to the negation operator Op¬ in the left periphery would enable the disjunction to scope under negation. Movement is thus the cause of the obviation effect but it is unclear what mechanism gives rise to the anti-licensing effect in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper sketches, instead, a meaning-based account of both the positive-polarity behaviour of the plain disjunction marker &lt;em&gt;ili&lt;/em&gt; and the circumstances of obviation. To account for the general pattern of the inability of &lt;em&gt;ili&lt;/em&gt; to scope under clausemate negation, I follow Nicolae (2017) in claiming that the scalar inference accompanying disjunction arises due to the interaction of a covert exhaustification operator &lt;strong&gt;Exh&lt;/strong&gt; and a covert necessity modal, which renders the otherwise non-innocently excludable alternatives in upward-entailing contexts innocently excludable. In the case of plain disjunction (as opposed to complex disjunction, Spector 2014), the exhaustifier &lt;strong&gt;Exh&lt;/strong&gt; only manipulates domain alternatives. The incompatibility with negation results, on this view, from a ban on vacuous exhaustification: if an LF containing Exh does not yield a strengthened meaning, it is ruled inadmissible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two sets of facts speak in favour of a meaning-based analysis of PPI obviation effects when the disjunction phrase undergoes Ā-movement: (i) obviation is sensitive to the interpretation of the Ā-moved item (topic; *focus); (ii) when multiple disjunction phrases are fronted, only one, rather than all, of them can scope under negation. Topicalisation would create additional alternatives alongside the already defined domain alternatives, and exhaustification would not be vacuous. This is in line with Nicolae’s (2017) suggestion that PPI-disjunctions take into account both the truth-conditional and non-truth-conditional meaning. On this view, fronting will not be the cause of obviation effect but rather a byproduct of topicality, given the fact that Russian topics are typically fronted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can view the slides &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavelrudnev.github.io/papers/farl2019-slides.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Talk at FARL 3</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2019/farl3-talk/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2019/farl3-talk/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently given a presentation at the third installment of the Formal Approaches to Russian Linguistics workshop at Lomonosov Moscow State University. In my talk, I have tried to adapt an exhaustification analysis of PPI-disjunction to the facts of Russian. An abstract and a set of slides are available &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/farl3/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Against Upwards Agree: A view from Daghestan</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/formlab-agreement/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/formlab-agreement/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This talk discusses a recent approach to ϕ-agreement as formulated in Bjorkman &amp;amp; Zeijlstra to appear. According to that approach, all probing relations are established by probing “upwards”, and all exceptions traditionally analysed as involving probing “downwards” are viewed as being parasitic on such Upwards-Agree relations. By looking at (ϕ)-agreement patterns in two morphologically ergative East-Caucasian languages, Mehweb and Avar, I identify what I view as insurmountable empirical hurdles to Bjorkman &amp;amp; Zeijlstra&amp;rsquo;s analysis. I also identify a number of conceptual issues with their analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can view the slides &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavelrudnev.github.io/papers/formal-lab-agreement-slides.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Features in Minimalist syntax</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/formlab-features/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/formlab-features/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This talks provides an overview of approaches to featural dependencies in current minimalist work starting from Chomsky (1995). I also discuss aspects of the theory of feature structure which, though often taken for granted, present non-trivial challenges to developing explanatory analyses of featural dependencies. In addition to ϕ-features, the features I discuss are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interpretable vs. uninterpretable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;valued vs. unvalued&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;second-order features/EPP-features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;features-of-features ([E]-features)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;formal wh-features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;formal information-structural features
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I conclude, in broad agreement with Šimík (2012) and Boeckx (2015), that the only domain where postulating formal features does not lead to problems are morphosyntactic agreement phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can view the (Russian-language) slides &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavelrudnev.github.io/papers/Presentation.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Automatic detection of natural phonological classes in Russian Sign Language</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/rsl-phonology/</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/rsl-phonology/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The present paper applies Multiple Correspondence Analysis to test the validity of an existing theoretical model of the phonological system of Russian Sign Language (RSL). We show that comparing the importance of phonological features using ratio plots and MCA is a promising way of revealing non-binary oppositions in phonological systems of human languages irrespective of modality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Agreeing adpositions in Avar and theories of Agree</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/agreeing-adpositions-in-avar/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/agreeing-adpositions-in-avar/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Given the central spot afforded to unvalued features in current
minimalist theorizing, the directionality of feature valuation is the
subject of a lively debate in the syntactic literature. The
traditional conception of upward valuation, whereby the unvalued probe
inherits features from a valued goal in its c-command domain (Chomsky
2000, 2001, Carstens &amp;amp; Diercks 2013, Preminger 2013), has to compete
with downward valuation (Zeijlstra 2012), Hybrid Agree (Bjorkman &amp;amp;
Zeijlstra to appear), bidirectional Agree (Baker 2008), amongst others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk discusses, using data from Avar, a crosslinguistically rare
phenomenon of adposition agreement, whereby certain adverbs,
postpositions and locative-marked noun phrases undergo agreement with
an absolutive argument. I show that the agreement morphology on
agreeing adpositions is a result of agreement rather than concord, and
explore the consequences of adposition agreement in Avar for upward
and downward valuation. I conclude that the traditional conception of
upward valuation is both conceptually and empirically superior to its
alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>East Caucasian coordination</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/east-caucasian-disjunction/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/east-caucasian-disjunction/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This talk discusses East Caucasian coordination strategies from the viewpoint of recent decompositional approaches to “logical” vocabulary (words like &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; etc.) as pursued by Mitrović (2014). Focusing on the predictions of that analysis concerning the unavoidability of exclusivity inferences in the case of reduplicated pairs of μ- and κ-particles, I identify a disjunction strategy in Avar that casts doubt on the universality of the analysis and suggest possible workarounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The handout is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavelrudnev.github.io/papers/andic-seminar-26-10-2018.md.handout.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Some difficulties deriving the positive polarity behaviour of plain disjunction in Russian: Remarks on Nicolae 2017</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/ppi-disjunctions-in-russian-squib/</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/ppi-disjunctions-in-russian-squib/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nicolae (2017) develops an account of PPI-disjunctions whereby
the unacceptability of plain disjunction in DE-environments results from
an economy condition imposed on obligatory exhaustification. This remark
shows this general mechanism to be insufficient to account for the
behaviour of the Russian plain disjunction marker &lt;em&gt;ili&lt;/em&gt;, whose scope properties are
argued to correlate with the phrasal vs. clausal nature of the disjunction:
phrasal disjunction yields narrow scope whilst clausal disjunction yields
wide scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper is currently down for revision; yet, if you feel you would like an intermediate draft of it, please get in touch with me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Minimalism: Linguistic theory and considerations of simplicity</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/hse-spb-minimalism/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/hse-spb-minimalism/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This is an invited guest lecture for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hse.ru/org/persons/191262608&#34;&gt;Misha Knyazev&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s undergraduate course on theoretical approaches in linguistics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Classes</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/</guid>
<description></description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Formal Representation of Natural Language</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2018/hse-frnl/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2018/hse-frnl/</guid>
<description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course will provide the following learning outcomes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To understand the logic behind several important theories of syntax and its interactions with sound and meaning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To be able to apply that understanding to evaluate the relevance of those theories and their limitations with respect to Russian.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To be able to apply the scientific method to analyse several empirical phenomena in Russian.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;assessment&#34;&gt;Assessment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course will be assessed by one 4,500-word essay critically reviewing one original research article pertaining to the course&amp;rsquo;s main topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;preliminary-timeline&#34;&gt;Preliminary timeline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lecture-1-introduction&#34;&gt;Lecture 1: Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grammar as science

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the scientific method (descriptive and explanatory &lt;em&gt;vs.&lt;/em&gt; prescriptive; potential clashes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;asbtract models of knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hierarchical structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;word classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lexical and functional categories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lecture-2-syntax&#34;&gt;Lecture 2: Syntax&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fundamental concepts

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;morphemes, words, phrases, sentences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;heads and their dependents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;constituent structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;constituency tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;structural relations
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lecture-3-syntax&#34;&gt;Lecture 3: Syntax&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sentences and constituents

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adjuncts, complements and specifiers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;syntactic processes

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;movement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;restrictions on movement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lecture-4-syntax&#34;&gt;Lecture 4: Syntax&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;syntactic processes

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;movement and information structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scrambling, focus fronting, topicalisation
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lecture-5-syntax-semantics&#34;&gt;Lecture 5: Syntax/Semantics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negation and polarity in Russian

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;negative concord, polarity licensing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;positive polarity and disjunction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lecture-6-semantics&#34;&gt;Lecture 6: Semantics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meaning and structure

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compositionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;syntax-to-semantics mapping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;semantics primer: sets and functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lecture-7-semantics&#34;&gt;Lecture 7: Semantics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fundamentals of tense, aspect and &lt;em&gt;aktionsart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tense and aspect in clausal architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lexical and superlexical prefixes in Russian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Plain disjunction markers in Russian and positive polarity</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/sle-2018/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/sle-2018/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: We know since at least Szabolcsi (2002) that disjunction markers in certain languages display remarkable similarities with some in English, similarities attributable to both groups of elements’ status as positive polarity items. In the case of disjunction, this translates into the inability of disjunction to scope under a local sentential negation leading to violations of De Morgan’s laws: &lt;em&gt;He doesn’t speak Russian or German&lt;/em&gt; in Russian can under certain circumstances be interpreted as a disjunction of negations, the narrow scope reading being unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current consensus in the literature seems to be that positive polarity is a semantic phenomenon. In this talk I suggest that positive polarity has an important syntactic component, which I show by revisiting the locality of (anti-)licensing, rescuing, the phrasal vs. clausal coordination as well as overt movement and scope in Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a peer-reviewed talk, for the 51st annual meeting of the Societas Linguistica Europæa at Tallinn University.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Grant from the Russian Science Foundation</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2018/rscf-grant/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2018/rscf-grant/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A team of researchers at HSE, including myself, has recently been awarded a highly competitive and prestigious grant by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rscf.ru&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Russian Science Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Over the next few years, we&amp;rsquo;ll be investigating non-finite constructions in a number of severely understudied languages of Russia (Avar, Bagwalal, Udi, Agul, Hill Mari, Meadow Mari, Northern Khanty, Chukchi). The project&amp;rsquo;s title is &lt;em&gt;When the verb isn&amp;rsquo;t a verb: Non-finite constructions in the languages of Russia&lt;/em&gt;, and you can read more about it &lt;a href=&#34;http://rscf.ru/en/enprjcard/?rid=18-78-10128&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Theory in Language Description</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2018/hse-theory-language-description/</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2018/hse-theory-language-description/</guid>
<description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course will provide the following learning outcomes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learning the architecture and the internal logic of individual theoretical models on various levels of language
structure, including phonology, morphophonology, syntax, semantics and discourse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developing skills in application of these theories in modelling empirical data and describing individual
languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;training in formal and not-so-formal linguistic theories and way of theoretical thinking they are associated
with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic for my part of this course is &lt;strong&gt;Modularity in linguistic theory&lt;/strong&gt;, and the discussion will focus on the tension between Minimalism and Cartography and the relationship between syntax and information structure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Avar negation (talk at the Russian Academy of Sciences)</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/avar-negation-talk-ras/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/avar-negation-talk-ras/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently presented my ongoing work on the syntactico-semantic properties of negation in Avar in the Andic seminar at the Institute of Linguistics of the Russian Academy of Sciences. This was my first Russian-language presentation after a long lull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the talk, I argued that the rather idiosyncratic morphosyntactic properties of Avar negation, as well as the restrictions on the expression and interpretation of negation, can be accounted for in a framework postulating an ontological distinction between (sets of) events and (sets of) situations as conceptual underpinnings of the hierarchy of functional projections. In particular, I proposed that two negation strategies coëxist in Avar: a monoclausal one, familiar from better-studied languages, operates on non-past tense clauses, and the predicative one where the negation marker is essentially a copula which combines with a nominalised clause, expresses negation in the past tense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The handout (in Russian) can be downloaded &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavelrudnev.github.io/papers/avar-negation-andi-seminar-ras-handout.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>The nature of restrictions on the expression of negation in Avar</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/on-the-nature-of-restrictions-on-avar-negation-ras/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/on-the-nature-of-restrictions-on-avar-negation-ras/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently presented my ongoing work on the syntactico-semantic properties of negation in Avar in the Andic seminar at the Institute of Linguistics of the Russian Academy of Sciences. This was my first Russian-language presentation after a long lull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the talk, I argued that the rather idiosyncratic morphosyntactic properties of Avar negation, as well as the restrictions on the expression and interpretation of negation, can be accounted for in a framework postulating an ontological distinction between (sets of) events and (sets of) situations as conceptual underpinnings of the hierarchy of functional projections. In particular, I proposed that two negation strategies coëxist in Avar: a monoclausal one, familiar from better-studied languages, operates on non-past tense clauses, and the predicative one where the negation marker is essentially a copula which combines with a nominalised clause, expresses negation in the past tense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The handout (in Russian) can be downloaded &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavelrudnev.github.io/papers/avar-negation-andi-seminar-ras-handout.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Disjunct size, positive polarity and the scope of disjunction in Russian</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/disjunct-size-iatl/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/disjunct-size-iatl/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: In this talk I show that the positive-polarity status of the plain disjunction marker &lt;em&gt;ili&lt;/em&gt; ‘or’ in Russian correlates with the phrasal vs. clausal nature of disjunction. In particular, I demonstrate that appealing to the availability of phrasal disjunction can shed some light on the hitherto unobserved obviations of anti-licensing effects characteristic of PPI-disjunction markers in a variety of languages (Szabolcsi 2002 &lt;em&gt;et seq.&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a peer-reviewed talk, for the 33rd annual meeting of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iatl.org.il/?page_id=1139&#34;&gt;Israel Association for Theoretical Linguistics&lt;/a&gt;, in Tel-Aviv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can view the slides &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavelrudnev.github.io/papers/iatl33-slides-rudnev.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Formal Models in Linguistics</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2017/hse-formal-models/</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2017/hse-formal-models/</guid>
<description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course will provide the following learning outcomes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To understand the logic behind several important theories of syntax and its interactions with sound and meaning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To be able to apply that understanding to evaluate the relevance of those theories and their limitations with respect to Russian.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To be able to apply the scientific method to analyse several empirical phenomena in Russian.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;assessment&#34;&gt;Assessment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course will be assessed by one 4,500-word essay critically reviewing one original research article pertaining to the course&amp;rsquo;s main topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;preliminary-timeline&#34;&gt;Preliminary timeline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lecture-1-introduction&#34;&gt;Lecture 1: Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grammar as science

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the scientific method (descriptive and explanatory &lt;em&gt;vs.&lt;/em&gt; prescriptive; potential clashes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;asbtract models of knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hierarchical structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;word classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lexical and functional categories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lecture-2-syntax&#34;&gt;Lecture 2: Syntax&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fundamental concepts

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;morphemes, words, phrases, sentences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;heads and their dependents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;constituent structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;constituency tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;structural relations
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lecture-3-syntax&#34;&gt;Lecture 3: Syntax&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sentences and constituents

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adjuncts, complements and specifiers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;syntactic processes

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;movement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;restrictions on movement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lecture-4-syntax&#34;&gt;Lecture 4: Syntax&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;syntactic processes

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;movement and information structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scrambling, focus fronting, topicalisation
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lecture-5-syntax-semantics&#34;&gt;Lecture 5: Syntax/Semantics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negation and polarity in Russian

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;negative concord, polarity licensing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;positive polarity and disjunction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lecture-6-semantics&#34;&gt;Lecture 6: Semantics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meaning and structure

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compositionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;syntax-to-semantics mapping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;semantics primer: sets and functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lecture-7-semantics&#34;&gt;Lecture 7: Semantics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fundamentals of tense, aspect and &lt;em&gt;aktionsart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tense and aspect in clausal architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lexical and superlexical prefixes in Russian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>IATL 33</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/upcoming-iatl33-presentation/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/upcoming-iatl33-presentation/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I will present my recent work on the PPI-behaviour of the Russian plain disjunction marker &lt;em&gt;ili&lt;/em&gt; at the 33rd annual meeting of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iatl.org.il/?page_id=1139&#34;&gt;Israel Association for Theoretical Linguistics&lt;/a&gt;. In the talk, I argue that that behaviour as well as the apparent exceptions can be derived from the phrasal versus clausal character of the disjunction, and the status of Russian as a negative concord language.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>New job come September</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/new-job-hse/</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/new-job-hse/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been awarded a postdoctoral research fellowship in linguistics at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ling.hse.ru/en&#34;&gt;School of Linguistics&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hse.ru/en/&#34;&gt;National Research University Higher School of Economics&lt;/a&gt; in Moscow, to commence on 1 September 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Paths to positive polarity: PPI-disjunctions in Russian</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/paths-to-positive-polarity-farl/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/paths-to-positive-polarity-farl/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: We know since at least Szabolcsi (2002) that disjunction markers in certain languages display remarkable similarities with some in English, similarities attributable to both groups of elements’ status as positive polarity items. In the case of disjunction, this translates into the inability of disjunction to scope under a local sentential negation leading to violations of De Morgan’s laws: &lt;em&gt;He doesn’t speak Russian or German&lt;/em&gt; in Russian can under certain circumstances be interpreted as a disjunction of negations, the narrow scope reading being unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current consensus in the literature seems to be that positive polarity is a semantic phenomenon. In this talk I suggest that positive polarity has an important syntactic component, which I show by revisiting the locality of (anti-)licensing, rescuing, the phrasal vs. clausal coordination as well as overt movement and scope in Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a peer-reviewed talk, for the second installment of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://otipl.philol.msu.ru/library/seminars/farl/farl2_main.php&#34;&gt;Formal Approaches to Russian Linguistics&lt;/a&gt; workshop, in Moscow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>FARL 2017</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/farl-talk-2017/</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/farl-talk-2017/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I presented my recent work on the PPI-behaviour of the Russian plain disjunction markers &lt;em&gt;ili&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;libo&lt;/em&gt; at the second installment of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://otipl.philol.msu.ru/library/seminars/farl/farl2_main.php&#34;&gt;Formal Approaches to Russian Linguistics&lt;/a&gt; workshop in Moscow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>A New Paper</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/a-new-paper/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/a-new-paper/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;My paper on long-distance anaphora in Avar has finally appeared in &lt;em&gt;Studia Linguistica&lt;/em&gt;. In it I offer a detailed description of the distribution of two long-distance reflexives&amp;mdash;&lt;em&gt;žiwgo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;žiw&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this looks interesting to you, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavelrudnev.github.io/papers/minimalpronouns/&#34;&gt;take a look&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d appreciate your feedback. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Minimal pronouns, logophoricity, and long-distance reflexivisation in Avar</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/minimal-pronouns-logophoricity-avar/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/minimal-pronouns-logophoricity-avar/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This paper discusses two morphologically related anaphoric pronouns in Avar (Avar-Andic, Nakh-Daghestanian) and proposes that one of them should be treated as a minimal pronoun that receives its interpretation from a λ-operator situated on a phasal head whereas the other is a logophoric pronoun denoting the author of the reported event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>The syntactic side of positive polarity: PPI-disjunctions in Russian</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/syntactic-side-of-positive-polarity-leiden/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/syntactic-side-of-positive-polarity-leiden/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: We know since at least Szabolcsi (2002) that disjunction markers in certain languages display remarkable similarities with some in English, similarities attributable to both groups of elements’ status as positive polarity items. In the case of disjunction, this translates into the inability of disjunction to scope under a local sentential negation leading to violations of De Morgan’s laws: &lt;em&gt;He doesn’t speak Russian or German&lt;/em&gt; in Russian can under certain circumstances be interpreted as a disjunction of negations, the narrow scope reading being unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current consensus in the literature seems to be that positive polarity is a semantic phenomenon. In this talk I suggest that positive polarity has an important syntactic component, which I show by revisiting the locality of (anti-)licensing, rescuing, the phrasal vs. clausal coordination as well as overt movement and scope in Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an invited talk presented at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://romancelab.weblog.leidenuniv.nl/&#34;&gt;Comparative Syntax Meetings&lt;/a&gt; series at the University of Leiden, 15 September 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavelrudnev.github.io/papers/leiden-handout-2up.pdf&#34;&gt;handout is available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Particles, disjunctions and inquisitivity in Avar</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/disjunction-concessivity-avar-tabudag/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/disjunction-concessivity-avar-tabudag/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: This paper discusses a previously neglected disjunction strategy in Avar (NE Caucasian),
whereby each disjunct is accompanied by a morphologically complex disjunction
marker &lt;em&gt;=nigi&lt;/em&gt; yet the disjunction is not interpreted exclusively, unlike the reduplicated discontinuous disjunctions like &lt;em&gt;soit_soit&lt;/em&gt; in French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The disjunction marker is exponentially identical with the particle attaching to indefinites
and turning them into polarity items: &lt;em&gt;šib=nigi&lt;/em&gt; ‘what=POL (ie someting/nothing)’
as well as the marker of concessivity that attaches to verbs.
In this paper I attempt to unify the approach to particles developed by
Wiltschko (2016) with the analysis of particle float in Avar (Rudnev 2015).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a  talk presented at the 37th installment of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.let.rug.nl/tabudag/&#34;&gt;TaBu Dag&lt;/a&gt;, an annual general linguistics conference organised by the University of Groningen, 3rd June 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://pavelrudnev.github.io/papers/tabu-handout.pdf&#34;&gt;handout is available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternatively, you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://pavelrudnev.github.io/papers/tabu-slides.pdf&#34;&gt;view the slides here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Core and peripheral disjunction strategies in Russian: Their interaction with sentential negation</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/core-and-peripheral-disjunction-tindag/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/core-and-peripheral-disjunction-tindag/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This paper’s point of departure is the generalisation in Szabolcsi (2002) that natural languages differ in the way that their disjunction markers can be interpreted when embedded under negation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) Mary doesn’t speak German or Polish.&lt;br /&gt;
= Mary doesn’t speak German and she doesn’t speak Polish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corresponding sentences in Hungarian are interpreted exclusively: either Mary doesn’t speak German or she doesn’t speak Polish (Szabolcsi 2002). Szabolcsi (2002) proposes that the contrast between English and Hungarian lies in the status of Hungarian ‘or’ as a positive polarity item, in contrast to English or. In this talk I take a closer look at Russian, a language that Szabolcsi (2002) places in the Hungarian class, by revisiting Szabolcsi’s generalisation as it applies to Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://pavelrudnev.github.io/pdf/tindag2016-slides.pdf&#34;&gt;slides can be downloaded here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>LBU001B05: The Language Situation in the Low Countries</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2016/lbu001b05-lang-sit-low-count/</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2016/lbu001b05-lang-sit-low-count/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This course surveys the nature and history of the Dutch language and its position in
the Netherlands and Belgium today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction: the languages of the Netherlands and Belgium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Essentials of the Dutch language: phonology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Essentials of the Dutch language: syntax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The history of Dutch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The history of Dutch (cont’d)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dutch orthography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purism and school grammar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dialects of Dutch; Frisian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dutch-based creole languages; Afrikaans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dutch sociolinguistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>The interaction of disjunction and negation in Russian</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/disjunction-negation-in-russian-syntaxif/</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/disjunction-negation-in-russian-syntaxif/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The project takes as its point of departure the generalisation found in Szabolcsi (2002), which has become a standard reference point in the literature on negation and disjunction, that natural languages differ in the way that their disjunction markers can be interpreted when embedded under negation. Examples (1) and (2) illustrate the contrast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) Mary didn’t take hockey or algebra.&lt;br/&gt;
= ‘Mary took neither hockey nor algebra.’
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In languages like English the most salient interpretation of (1) is that Mary took neither hockey nor algebra, whereas it is seldom interpreted as saying that Mary didn’t take either of hockey or algebra together but that she may very well have taken one of them but not the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corresponding sentences in Hungarian, however, are interpreted in an entirely different manner:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) mari nem járt hokira vagy algebrára&lt;br/&gt;
  Mari not went hockey.to or algebra.to&lt;br/&gt;
   = ‘Mary didn’t take hockey and didn’t take algebra.’ &lt;br/&gt;
   = ‘Mary didn’t take hockey or didn’t take algebra.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Szabolcsi (2002) proposes that the contrast between the English (1) and (2) from Hungarian lies in the status of vagy ‘or’ as a positive polarity item (PPI), whereas in English or does not have such a status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Languages that have been argued to pattern with English as far as the interpretation of disjunction under negation is concerned include German and Dutch, whereas Romanian, Russian and Japanese are named as belonging to the same class of languages as Hungarian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk I revisit Szabolcsi’s (2002) generalisation as it applies to Russian, focusing on two potential problems: (i) the availability of only the conjunctive interpretation in negated copular clauses and (ii) the degraded status of Russian counterparts to (2).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an invited talk at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://syntaxif.wp.hum.uu.nl/&#34;&gt;Syntax Interface Lectures&lt;/a&gt; series at Utrecht University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://pavelrudnev.github.io/pdf/utrecht-handout-1up.pdf&#34;&gt;handout&lt;/a&gt; for this talk is available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Events, locations and situations: On the interaction of negation and finiteness in Avar</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/events-locations-and-situations/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/events-locations-and-situations/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This paper documents a number of restrictions on negation marking in Avar, a Northeast Caucasian language, and presents a tentative analysis of the observed morphosyntactic facts as having a semantic basis. The two different negation markers are analysed, based on the proposal in (Ramchand &amp;amp; Svenonius 2014), as taking complements of a different semantic type.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>LTX020P05: Syntaxis 1</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2015/zinsleer-groningen/</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2015/zinsleer-groningen/</guid>
<description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;De student is bekend met basisbegrippen uit de syntaxis, en is in staat deze te hanteren. In het bijzonder kan de student de belangrijkste morfosyntactische verschijnselen in vertrouwde en minder vertrouwde talen herkennen, analyseren en benoemen. Daarbij kan hij/zij geannoteerde taaldata lezen en begrijpen, en ook zelf taaldata annoteren volgens de wetenschappelijke standaard. (K1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;De student kan de syntactische structuur van een Nederlandse zin vaststellen door de onderdelen van de zin te identificeren en te benoemen, en de gekozen analyse te beargumenteren aan de hand van diagnostische tests.(K2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;De student kent basale syntactische analysemethoden.(K3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>BM ang060 Part 1:  Introduction to Linguistics and the English Language</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2015/basismodul-oldenburg/</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2015/basismodul-oldenburg/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This course introduces the basic concepts, methods and fields of linguistics and deals with language as a cognitive ability as well as language as a system. In the first term, special emphasis will be on the phonological, morphological and syntactic properties of English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 9 lectures grouped in blocks and interspersed by reading weeks (please, check &lt;a href=&#34;https://elearning.uni-oldenburg.de/dispatch.php/course/details/index/34bf203ee9731de1de5a44b708ed0ee9&#34;&gt;StudIP&lt;/a&gt; for the syllabus and exact dates and times).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course will be accompanied by weekly exercises, which are compulsory, accompany the lecture and independently treat the phonology of English (see StudIP for the syllabus). There are also optional tutorials which are highly recommended for getting accustomed to terminology and methodology. In summer, the module will be complemented by a course on the phonetics, semantics/pragmatics and history of the English language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading:&lt;/strong&gt; A reader will be distributed during the first lectures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The material for the phonology part will be made available as powerpoint presentations after each exercise session.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>_Kendisi_ revisited</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/kendisi-revisited/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/kendisi-revisited/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The present contribution follows up on Rudnev 2011, which, in turn, was based on a presentation I gave in Barbara Partee&amp;rsquo;s semantics class in the spring of 2008. It is for this reason that I omit most of the arguments for the pronominal nature of kendisi and present a formalisation of its semantic properties based on Partee 1983 and Elbourne 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>A study of Avar negation</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/avar-negation-groningen/</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/avar-negation-groningen/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk I discuss a number of restrictions on sentential negation marking in Avar, a Northeast Caucasian language, and sketch a tentative analysis of the observed morphosyntactic facts as having a semantic basis. The two different negation markers (&lt;em&gt;-ro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;-č&amp;rsquo;o&lt;/em&gt;) are analysed, based on the proposal in Ramchand &amp;amp; Svenonius 2014, as taking complements of a different syntactic size and semantic type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I show that the two negation markers attested in Avar differ in the type of semantic object they can compose with: for the present and future tenses &lt;em&gt;-ro&lt;/em&gt; combines with a Fin*P denoting a set of propositions, whereas past-tense negation utilises the biclausal predicational strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question why past tense forms cannot combine with &lt;em&gt;-ro&lt;/em&gt; has remained unanswered. It remains to be seen whether the proposal made for &lt;em&gt;-č’o&lt;/em&gt; can be made compatible with the use of the present-tense negative copula/auxiliary &lt;em&gt;heč’o&lt;/em&gt; as the auxiliary in analytic verb forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I further draw a number of cross-linguistic comparisons between Avar on the one hand, and Bengali, Mebengokre and the Salish languages on the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords:&lt;/strong&gt; syntax, semantics, negation, nominalization, event semantics, situation semantics, Avar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a talk at the [That depends&amp;hellip;]() workshop on the occasion of my viva at the University of Groningen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://pavelrudnev.github.io/pdf/that-depends-handout.pdf&#34;&gt;handout&lt;/a&gt; for this talk is available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Dependency and discourse-configurationality</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/dependency-and-discourse-configurationality/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/dependency-and-discourse-configurationality/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The present thesis provides a detailed description of the syntactic and semantic properties of a number of related constructions in Avar, a Northeast Caucasian language. These include relativisation, wh-questions and focus sentences, all of which are created via a dependency between an abstract operator and a variable. In addition to the description a generative analysis is developed whereby the relative clause is treated as the structural core for the remaining constructions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Locations and situations: Negation and finiteness in Avar</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/locations-and-situations-avar-negation-tindag/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/locations-and-situations-avar-negation-tindag/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk I discuss a number of restrictions on sentential negation marking in Avar, a Northeast Caucasian language, and sketch a tentative analysis of the observed morphosyntactic facts as having a semantic basis. The two different negation markers (&lt;em&gt;-ro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;-č&amp;rsquo;o&lt;/em&gt;) are analysed, based on the proposal in Ramchand &amp;amp; Svenonius 2014, as taking complements of a different syntactic size and semantic type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I show that the two negation markers attested in Avar differ in the type of semantic object they can compose with: for the present and future tenses &lt;em&gt;-ro&lt;/em&gt; combines with a Fin*P denoting a set of propositions, whereas past-tense negation utilises the biclausal predicational strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords:&lt;/strong&gt; syntax, semantics, negation, nominalization, event semantics, situation semantics, Avar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a talk at TiN-Dag 2015, the annual general linguistics conference of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hum.leidenuniv.nl/onderzoek/avt/&#34;&gt;Dutch Linguistics Association&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://pavelrudnev.github.io/pdf/tindag2015-handout.pdf&#34;&gt;handout&lt;/a&gt; for this talk is available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Towards a non-cartographic approach to Avar focus movement</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2013/avar-focus-goettingen/</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2013/avar-focus-goettingen/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk I examine the Avar focus construction, restricting my attention to situations where focus marking brings with it a change in the morphosyntactic appearance of the verb. I argue against the popular cartographic approach to focus whereby non-syntactic, interpretative information is instantiated as a head in the functional structure of the clause, and pursue an alternative, free-merge based approach to focus movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superseded by chapter 5 of my PhD thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords:&lt;/strong&gt; syntax, semantics, focus, Avar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an invited talk at &lt;em&gt;New approaches to the syntax/semantics interface&lt;/em&gt;, a workshop held at the University of Göttingen as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.u4network.eu/&#34;&gt;U4 network&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://pavelrudnev.github.io/pdf/goettingen-slides.pdf&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt; for this talk are available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
<item>
<title>Matrix constituent interrogatives in Avar</title>
<link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2012/avar-wh-questions-istanbul/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2012/avar-wh-questions-istanbul/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk I examine two strategies of posing a matrix wh-question in Avar, restricting my attention to situations where focus marking brings with it a change in the morphosyntactic appearance of the verb. I argue against the popular wh-extraction approach, and analyse the two strategies as involving clefting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superseded by chapter 4 of my PhD thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords:&lt;/strong&gt; syntax, semantics, wh-questions, Avar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a peer-reviewed talk at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caucasus.boun.edu.tr/&#34;&gt;Typology, theory: Caucasus&lt;/a&gt;, a conference co-hosted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://boun.edu.tr&#34;&gt;Boğazici University&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ifea-istanbul.net/index.php?option=com_k2&amp;amp;view=item&amp;amp;layout=item&amp;amp;id=1255&amp;amp;Itemid=295&amp;amp;lang=fr&#34;&gt;French Research Institute&lt;/a&gt; in Istanbul.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
