<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pavel Rudnev’s website</title>
    <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pavel Rudnev’s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pavelrudnev.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linearisation constraints on sentential negation in Russian Sign Language are prosodic</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/sll-squib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/sll-squib/</guid>
      <description>This short remark documents exceptions to the main strategy of expressing sentential negation in Russian Sign Language (RSL). The postverbal sentential negation particle in RSL inverts the basic SVO order characteristic of the language turning it into SOV. We show that this reversal requirement under negation is not absolute and does not apply to prosodically heavy object NPs. The resulting picture accords well with the view of RSL word order laid out by Kimmelman (2012) and supports a model of grammar where syntactic computation has access to phonological information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Russian small nominals</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2021/bgu-small-nominals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2021/bgu-small-nominals/</guid>
      <description>Many approaches to the syntax of nominal phrases postulate the existence of nominals of various size so that some modifiers — determiners, quantifiers and classifiers — are argued to project a constituent of their own, such as DP, QP and ClP. As discussed by Salzmann (2020), most of the existing arguments do not in fact show that it is the modifier that is the head of the entire nominal constituent and are instead based on essentially semantic notions like referentiality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avar non-finites between restructuring and periphrasis</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2021/ghent-periphrasis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2021/ghent-periphrasis/</guid>
      <description>In many languages, forms traditionally characterised as nonfinite (participles, infinitives, converbs and gerunds/nominalisations) can either head a clausal constituent of their own or occur inside a periphrastic TAM-construction. Existing theoretical approaches to the morphosyntax of such elements postulate a range of mechanisms — both narrow-syntactic such as head movement and post-syntactic such as structure removal, impoverishment, underspecification or fusion — to enable the insertion of an identical form into two distinct syntactic structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Against Upwards Agree</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/against-ua/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/against-ua/</guid>
      <description>Bjorkman &amp;amp; Zeijlstra (2019) claim that agreement with the absolutive argument in ergative-absolutive languages follows naturally in an Upwards-Agree system supplemented by the relation of Accessibility if φ-agreement is parasitic on structural case assigned to the absolutive noun phrase either by T° or by v°. By drawing evidence from two distantly related East Caucasian languages—Chirag and Avar—the present article argues that this theory is both too strong and too weak. I then show that the problematical facts are trivially analysable with standard Agree (Chomsky 2000 et seq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Anaphor Agreement Effect: An East-Caucasian perspective</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2021/paris-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2021/paris-webinar/</guid>
      <description>The Anaphor Agreement Effect (AAE) is an empirical observation stating that reflexive pronouns tend to fail to trigger non-trivial φ-agreement on the verb (Rizzi 1990, Murugesan 2019, Preminger 2019).
Theoretical approaches to anaphora seeking to reduce reflexive binding to agreement postulate an inherent featural deficiency for referentially dependent expressions (Kratzer 2009, Rooryck &amp;amp; Vanden Wyngaerd 2011, Murugesan 2019). If it is not resolved via Agree during the derivation, the resulting structure either spells out trivial/defaul agreement (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agreeing adpositions in Avar and the directionality of valuation debate</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/agreeing-adpositions-in-avar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/agreeing-adpositions-in-avar/</guid>
      <description>Given the central spot afforded to unvalued features in current theorizing, the directionality of feature valuation is the subject of a lively debate in the syntactic literature. The traditional conception of upward valuation, whereby the unvalued probe inherits features from a valued goal in its c-command domain (Chomsky 2000, 2001a, Carstens 2013, Preminger 2013), has to compete with downward valuation (Zeijlstra 2012), Hybrid Agree (Bjorkman &amp;amp; Zeijlstra 2018), bidirectional Agree (Baker 2008), amongst others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In support of post-syntactic head movement: Loanword accommodation in Kunbarlang verb phrases</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2020/tmp2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2020/tmp2020/</guid>
      <description>(with Ivan Kapitonov)
Since the early 1990s the verb phrase is generally thought to be built from acategorial roots which are categorised via Merge with functional projections, such as v (see e.g. Marantz 1997). One of the questions about this architecture concerns the nature of head movement: is it syntactic (e.g. Travis 1984) or post-syntactic (e.g. Platzack 2013). In this paper we adduce novel data to argue that it cannot be reduced just to the former option (contra e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not all obligatory control is movement</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/oblique-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/oblique-control/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents two challenges for the analysis of promise-type verbs within the Movement Theory of Control. We show that the objects of these verbs in Russian are not prepositional and are incorrectly predicted to be legitimate controllers. We also argue, based on the patterns of polarity licensing, scope licensing and case marking on floating quantifiers, against analysing oblique control as sidewards movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case marking in Russian eventive nominalisations revisited</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/russian-nominalisations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/russian-nominalisations/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we analyse case marking in Russian eventive nominalisations recently discussed in Pereltsvaig 2018 with regards to two competing theories of case: the Inherent Case Theory (Woolford 2006; 2009) and the Dependent Case Theory (Marantz 1991). We contest the view that Russian eventive nominalisations display ergative alignment (Koptjevskaja-Tamm 1993) and argue that Russian is a nominative-accusative language across the board. We propose an analysis for the syntax of Russian eventive nominalisations and show that, contrary to Pereltsvaig (2018), they are in principle incapable of disproving the DCT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Anaphor Agreement Effect is not about featural deficiency: Evidence from Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/aae-squib/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/aae-squib/</guid>
      <description>This paper discusses two analyses of the Anaphor Agreement Effect (AAE, Rizzi 1990) in the light of novel data from Avar. By demonstrating that Avar anaphors trigger full, non-trivial agreement on the ϕ-probe, I argue that the Avar data instantiate a genuine exception to the AAE. I then compare two competing analyses of binding and the AAE: an account whereby anaphoric dependencies arise via the syntactic operation Agree (Murugesan 2018), and a theory deriving the inability of the anaphors’ ϕ-features to trigger full agreement from the presence of additional structural layers inside the anaphors that render the features inaccessible (Preminger 2019).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic locality, split ergativity and adposition agreement in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/iatl-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/iatl-2019/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: In this talk, I develop a configurational approach to case and agreement in the Avar biabsolutive constructions.
This is a peer-reviewed talk, for the 35th annual meeting of the Israel Association for Theoretical Linguistics, at The Open University in Ra&amp;rsquo;anana.
You can view the slides here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic locality, split ergativity and adposition agreement in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/lagb2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/lagb2019/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: In this talk, I develop a configurational approach to case and agreement in the Avar biabsolutive constructions.
This is a peer-reviewed talk, for the 2019 Annual Meeting of the Linguistics Association of Great Britain at Queen Mary University of London.
You can view the slides here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic phases, split ergativity and adposition agreement in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/camcos8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/camcos8/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: In this talk, I develop a configurational approach to case and agreement in the Avar biabsolutive constructions.
This is a peer-reviewed talk, for the 8th installment of Cambridge Comparative Syntax at St John&amp;rsquo;s College, Cambridge.
You can view the slides here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks at CamCoS 8 and SLE 52</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2019/camcos8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2019/camcos8/</guid>
      <description>In the spring/summer of 2019, I will give peer-reviewed talks at the eighth installment of the Cambridge Comparative Syntax conference (CamCoS) at the University of Cambridge and the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Societas Linguistica Europæa in Leipzig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk at FARL 3</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2019/farl3-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2019/farl3-talk/</guid>
      <description>I have recently given a presentation at the third installment of the Formal Approaches to Russian Linguistics workshop at Lomonosov Moscow State University. In my talk, I have tried to adapt an exhaustification analysis of PPI-disjunction to the facts of Russian. An abstract and a set of slides are available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards an exhaustification analysis of plain disjunction in Russian</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/farl3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/farl3/</guid>
      <description>It has been known since at least Szabolcsi 2002 that the Russian plain disjunction marker ili behaves as a positive polarity item (PPI) when occurring under clausemate negation, which manifests itself in a violation of De Morgan’s laws. Among properties which the Russian plain disjunction marker ili shares with conventional PPIs such as some are the locality of anti-licensing and the ability to be rescued by a second negation.
The Russian plain disjunction marker ili displays variable behaviour with respect to PPI-hood when interacting with Ā-movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Against Upwards Agree: A view from Daghestan</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/formlab-agreement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/formlab-agreement/</guid>
      <description>This talk discusses a recent approach to ϕ-agreement as formulated in Bjorkman &amp;amp; Zeijlstra to appear. According to that approach, all probing relations are established by probing “upwards”, and all exceptions traditionally analysed as involving probing “downwards” are viewed as being parasitic on such Upwards-Agree relations. By looking at (ϕ)-agreement patterns in two morphologically ergative East-Caucasian languages, Mehweb and Avar, I identify what I view as insurmountable empirical hurdles to Bjorkman &amp;amp; Zeijlstra&amp;rsquo;s analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Features in Minimalist syntax</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/formlab-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/formlab-features/</guid>
      <description>This talks provides an overview of approaches to featural dependencies in current minimalist work starting from Chomsky (1995). I also discuss aspects of the theory of feature structure which, though often taken for granted, present non-trivial challenges to developing explanatory analyses of featural dependencies. In addition to ϕ-features, the features I discuss are as follows:
 interpretable vs. uninterpretable valued vs. unvalued second-order features/EPP-features features-of-features ([E]-features) formal wh-features formal information-structural features   I conclude, in broad agreement with Šimík (2012) and Boeckx (2015), that the only domain where postulating formal features does not lead to problems are morphosyntactic agreement phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic detection of natural phonological classes in Russian Sign Language</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/rsl-phonology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/rsl-phonology/</guid>
      <description>The present paper applies Multiple Correspondence Analysis to test the validity of an existing theoretical model of the phonological system of Russian Sign Language (RSL). We show that comparing the importance of phonological features using ratio plots and MCA is a promising way of revealing non-binary oppositions in phonological systems of human languages irrespective of modality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agreeing adpositions in Avar and theories of Agree</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/agreeing-adpositions-in-avar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/agreeing-adpositions-in-avar/</guid>
      <description>Given the central spot afforded to unvalued features in current minimalist theorizing, the directionality of feature valuation is the subject of a lively debate in the syntactic literature. The traditional conception of upward valuation, whereby the unvalued probe inherits features from a valued goal in its c-command domain (Chomsky 2000, 2001, Carstens &amp;amp; Diercks 2013, Preminger 2013), has to compete with downward valuation (Zeijlstra 2012), Hybrid Agree (Bjorkman &amp;amp; Zeijlstra to appear), bidirectional Agree (Baker 2008), amongst others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>East Caucasian coordination</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/east-caucasian-disjunction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/east-caucasian-disjunction/</guid>
      <description>This talk discusses East Caucasian coordination strategies from the viewpoint of recent decompositional approaches to “logical” vocabulary (words like and, or, not etc.) as pursued by Mitrović (2014). Focusing on the predictions of that analysis concerning the unavoidability of exclusivity inferences in the case of reduplicated pairs of μ- and κ-particles, I identify a disjunction strategy in Avar that casts doubt on the universality of the analysis and suggest possible workarounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some difficulties deriving the positive polarity behaviour of plain disjunction in Russian: Remarks on Nicolae 2017</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/ppi-disjunctions-in-russian-squib/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/ppi-disjunctions-in-russian-squib/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Nicolae (2017) develops an account of PPI-disjunctions whereby the unacceptability of plain disjunction in DE-environments results from an economy condition imposed on obligatory exhaustification. This remark shows this general mechanism to be insufficient to account for the behaviour of the Russian plain disjunction marker ili, whose scope properties are argued to correlate with the phrasal vs. clausal nature of the disjunction: phrasal disjunction yields narrow scope whilst clausal disjunction yields wide scope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimalism: Linguistic theory and considerations of simplicity</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/hse-spb-minimalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/hse-spb-minimalism/</guid>
      <description>This is an invited guest lecture for Misha Knyazev&amp;rsquo;s undergraduate course on theoretical approaches in linguistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formal Representation of Natural Language</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2018/hse-frnl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2018/hse-frnl/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The course will provide the following learning outcomes:
 To understand the logic behind several important theories of syntax and its interactions with sound and meaning. To be able to apply that understanding to evaluate the relevance of those theories and their limitations with respect to Russian. To be able to apply the scientific method to analyse several empirical phenomena in Russian.  Assessment The course will be assessed by one 4,500-word essay critically reviewing one original research article pertaining to the course&amp;rsquo;s main topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plain disjunction markers in Russian and positive polarity</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/sle-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/sle-2018/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: We know since at least Szabolcsi (2002) that disjunction markers in certain languages display remarkable similarities with some in English, similarities attributable to both groups of elements’ status as positive polarity items. In the case of disjunction, this translates into the inability of disjunction to scope under a local sentential negation leading to violations of De Morgan’s laws: He doesn’t speak Russian or German in Russian can under certain circumstances be interpreted as a disjunction of negations, the narrow scope reading being unavailable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant from the Russian Science Foundation</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2018/rscf-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2018/rscf-grant/</guid>
      <description>A team of researchers at HSE, including myself, has recently been awarded a highly competitive and prestigious grant by the Russian Science Foundation. Over the next few years, we&amp;rsquo;ll be investigating non-finite constructions in a number of severely understudied languages of Russia (Avar, Bagwalal, Udi, Agul, Hill Mari, Meadow Mari, Northern Khanty, Chukchi). The project&amp;rsquo;s title is When the verb isn&amp;rsquo;t a verb: Non-finite constructions in the languages of Russia, and you can read more about it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory in Language Description</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2018/hse-theory-language-description/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2018/hse-theory-language-description/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The course will provide the following learning outcomes:
 learning the architecture and the internal logic of individual theoretical models on various levels of language structure, including phonology, morphophonology, syntax, semantics and discourse developing skills in application of these theories in modelling empirical data and describing individual languages training in formal and not-so-formal linguistic theories and way of theoretical thinking they are associated with  The topic for my part of this course is Modularity in linguistic theory, and the discussion will focus on the tension between Minimalism and Cartography and the relationship between syntax and information structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avar negation (talk at the Russian Academy of Sciences)</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/avar-negation-talk-ras/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/avar-negation-talk-ras/</guid>
      <description>I have recently presented my ongoing work on the syntactico-semantic properties of negation in Avar in the Andic seminar at the Institute of Linguistics of the Russian Academy of Sciences. This was my first Russian-language presentation after a long lull.
In the talk, I argued that the rather idiosyncratic morphosyntactic properties of Avar negation, as well as the restrictions on the expression and interpretation of negation, can be accounted for in a framework postulating an ontological distinction between (sets of) events and (sets of) situations as conceptual underpinnings of the hierarchy of functional projections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The nature of restrictions on the expression of negation in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/on-the-nature-of-restrictions-on-avar-negation-ras/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/on-the-nature-of-restrictions-on-avar-negation-ras/</guid>
      <description>I have recently presented my ongoing work on the syntactico-semantic properties of negation in Avar in the Andic seminar at the Institute of Linguistics of the Russian Academy of Sciences. This was my first Russian-language presentation after a long lull.
In the talk, I argued that the rather idiosyncratic morphosyntactic properties of Avar negation, as well as the restrictions on the expression and interpretation of negation, can be accounted for in a framework postulating an ontological distinction between (sets of) events and (sets of) situations as conceptual underpinnings of the hierarchy of functional projections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disjunct size, positive polarity and the scope of disjunction in Russian</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/disjunct-size-iatl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/disjunct-size-iatl/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: In this talk I show that the positive-polarity status of the plain disjunction marker ili ‘or’ in Russian correlates with the phrasal vs. clausal nature of disjunction. In particular, I demonstrate that appealing to the availability of phrasal disjunction can shed some light on the hitherto unobserved obviations of anti-licensing effects characteristic of PPI-disjunction markers in a variety of languages (Szabolcsi 2002 et seq.).
This is a peer-reviewed talk, for the 33rd annual meeting of the Israel Association for Theoretical Linguistics, in Tel-Aviv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formal Models in Linguistics</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2017/hse-formal-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2017/hse-formal-models/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The course will provide the following learning outcomes:
 To understand the logic behind several important theories of syntax and its interactions with sound and meaning. To be able to apply that understanding to evaluate the relevance of those theories and their limitations with respect to Russian. To be able to apply the scientific method to analyse several empirical phenomena in Russian.  Assessment The course will be assessed by one 4,500-word essay critically reviewing one original research article pertaining to the course&amp;rsquo;s main topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IATL 33</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/upcoming-iatl33-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/upcoming-iatl33-presentation/</guid>
      <description>I will present my recent work on the PPI-behaviour of the Russian plain disjunction marker ili at the 33rd annual meeting of the Israel Association for Theoretical Linguistics. In the talk, I argue that that behaviour as well as the apparent exceptions can be derived from the phrasal versus clausal character of the disjunction, and the status of Russian as a negative concord language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New job come September</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/new-job-hse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/new-job-hse/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been awarded a postdoctoral research fellowship in linguistics at the School of Linguistics at the National Research University Higher School of Economics in Moscow, to commence on 1 September 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FARL 2017</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/farl-talk-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/farl-talk-2017/</guid>
      <description>I presented my recent work on the PPI-behaviour of the Russian plain disjunction markers ili and libo at the second installment of the Formal Approaches to Russian Linguistics workshop in Moscow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paths to positive polarity: PPI-disjunctions in Russian</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/paths-to-positive-polarity-farl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/paths-to-positive-polarity-farl/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: We know since at least Szabolcsi (2002) that disjunction markers in certain languages display remarkable similarities with some in English, similarities attributable to both groups of elements’ status as positive polarity items. In the case of disjunction, this translates into the inability of disjunction to scope under a local sentential negation leading to violations of De Morgan’s laws: He doesn’t speak Russian or German in Russian can under certain circumstances be interpreted as a disjunction of negations, the narrow scope reading being unavailable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Paper</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/a-new-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/news/2017/a-new-paper/</guid>
      <description>My paper on long-distance anaphora in Avar has finally appeared in Studia Linguistica. In it I offer a detailed description of the distribution of two long-distance reflexives&amp;mdash;žiwgo and žiw.
If this looks interesting to you, please take a look. I&amp;rsquo;d appreciate your feedback. Thanks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimal pronouns, logophoricity, and long-distance reflexivisation in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/minimal-pronouns-logophoricity-avar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/minimal-pronouns-logophoricity-avar/</guid>
      <description>This paper discusses two morphologically related anaphoric pronouns in Avar (Avar-Andic, Nakh-Daghestanian) and proposes that one of them should be treated as a minimal pronoun that receives its interpretation from a λ-operator situated on a phasal head whereas the other is a logophoric pronoun denoting the author of the reported event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The syntactic side of positive polarity: PPI-disjunctions in Russian</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/syntactic-side-of-positive-polarity-leiden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/syntactic-side-of-positive-polarity-leiden/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: We know since at least Szabolcsi (2002) that disjunction markers in certain languages display remarkable similarities with some in English, similarities attributable to both groups of elements’ status as positive polarity items. In the case of disjunction, this translates into the inability of disjunction to scope under a local sentential negation leading to violations of De Morgan’s laws: He doesn’t speak Russian or German in Russian can under certain circumstances be interpreted as a disjunction of negations, the narrow scope reading being unavailable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Particles, disjunctions and inquisitivity in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/disjunction-concessivity-avar-tabudag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/disjunction-concessivity-avar-tabudag/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: This paper discusses a previously neglected disjunction strategy in Avar (NE Caucasian), whereby each disjunct is accompanied by a morphologically complex disjunction marker =nigi yet the disjunction is not interpreted exclusively, unlike the reduplicated discontinuous disjunctions like soit_soit in French.
The disjunction marker is exponentially identical with the particle attaching to indefinites and turning them into polarity items: šib=nigi ‘what=POL (ie someting/nothing)’ as well as the marker of concessivity that attaches to verbs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Core and peripheral disjunction strategies in Russian: Their interaction with sentential negation</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/core-and-peripheral-disjunction-tindag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/core-and-peripheral-disjunction-tindag/</guid>
      <description>This paper’s point of departure is the generalisation in Szabolcsi (2002) that natural languages differ in the way that their disjunction markers can be interpreted when embedded under negation.
(1) Mary doesn’t speak German or Polish.
= Mary doesn’t speak German and she doesn’t speak Polish.
Corresponding sentences in Hungarian are interpreted exclusively: either Mary doesn’t speak German or she doesn’t speak Polish (Szabolcsi 2002). Szabolcsi (2002) proposes that the contrast between English and Hungarian lies in the status of Hungarian ‘or’ as a positive polarity item, in contrast to English or.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LBU001B05: The Language Situation in the Low Countries</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2016/lbu001b05-lang-sit-low-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2016/lbu001b05-lang-sit-low-count/</guid>
      <description>This course surveys the nature and history of the Dutch language and its position in the Netherlands and Belgium today.
 Introduction: the languages of the Netherlands and Belgium Essentials of the Dutch language: phonology Essentials of the Dutch language: syntax The history of Dutch The history of Dutch (cont’d) Dutch orthography Purism and school grammar Dialects of Dutch; Frisian Dutch-based creole languages; Afrikaans Dutch sociolinguistics  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The interaction of disjunction and negation in Russian</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/disjunction-negation-in-russian-syntaxif/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/disjunction-negation-in-russian-syntaxif/</guid>
      <description>The project takes as its point of departure the generalisation found in Szabolcsi (2002), which has become a standard reference point in the literature on negation and disjunction, that natural languages differ in the way that their disjunction markers can be interpreted when embedded under negation. Examples (1) and (2) illustrate the contrast.
(1) Mary didn’t take hockey or algebra. = ‘Mary took neither hockey nor algebra.’ 
In languages like English the most salient interpretation of (1) is that Mary took neither hockey nor algebra, whereas it is seldom interpreted as saying that Mary didn’t take either of hockey or algebra together but that she may very well have taken one of them but not the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Events, locations and situations: On the interaction of negation and finiteness in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/events-locations-and-situations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/events-locations-and-situations/</guid>
      <description>This paper documents a number of restrictions on negation marking in Avar, a Northeast Caucasian language, and presents a tentative analysis of the observed morphosyntactic facts as having a semantic basis. The two different negation markers are analysed, based on the proposal in (Ramchand &amp;amp; Svenonius 2014), as taking complements of a different semantic type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BM ang060 Part 1:  Introduction to Linguistics and the English Language</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2015/basismodul-oldenburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2015/basismodul-oldenburg/</guid>
      <description>This course introduces the basic concepts, methods and fields of linguistics and deals with language as a cognitive ability as well as language as a system. In the first term, special emphasis will be on the phonological, morphological and syntactic properties of English.
There are 9 lectures grouped in blocks and interspersed by reading weeks (please, check StudIP for the syllabus and exact dates and times).
The course will be accompanied by weekly exercises, which are compulsory, accompany the lecture and independently treat the phonology of English (see StudIP for the syllabus).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LTX020P05: Syntaxis 1</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2015/zinsleer-groningen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/class/2015/zinsleer-groningen/</guid>
      <description>De student is bekend met basisbegrippen uit de syntaxis, en is in staat deze te hanteren. In het bijzonder kan de student de belangrijkste morfosyntactische verschijnselen in vertrouwde en minder vertrouwde talen herkennen, analyseren en benoemen. Daarbij kan hij/zij geannoteerde taaldata lezen en begrijpen, en ook zelf taaldata annoteren volgens de wetenschappelijke standaard. (K1) De student kan de syntactische structuur van een Nederlandse zin vaststellen door de onderdelen van de zin te identificeren en te benoemen, en de gekozen analyse te beargumenteren aan de hand van diagnostische tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>_Kendisi_ revisited</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/kendisi-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/kendisi-revisited/</guid>
      <description>The present contribution follows up on Rudnev 2011, which, in turn, was based on a presentation I gave in Barbara Partee&amp;rsquo;s semantics class in the spring of 2008. It is for this reason that I omit most of the arguments for the pronominal nature of kendisi and present a formalisation of its semantic properties based on Partee 1983 and Elbourne 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A study of Avar negation</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/avar-negation-groningen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/avar-negation-groningen/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I discuss a number of restrictions on sentential negation marking in Avar, a Northeast Caucasian language, and sketch a tentative analysis of the observed morphosyntactic facts as having a semantic basis. The two different negation markers (-ro and -č&amp;rsquo;o) are analysed, based on the proposal in Ramchand &amp;amp; Svenonius 2014, as taking complements of a different syntactic size and semantic type.
In particular, I show that the two negation markers attested in Avar differ in the type of semantic object they can compose with: for the present and future tenses -ro combines with a Fin*P denoting a set of propositions, whereas past-tense negation utilises the biclausal predicational strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependency and discourse-configurationality</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/dependency-and-discourse-configurationality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/dependency-and-discourse-configurationality/</guid>
      <description>The present thesis provides a detailed description of the syntactic and semantic properties of a number of related constructions in Avar, a Northeast Caucasian language. These include relativisation, wh-questions and focus sentences, all of which are created via a dependency between an abstract operator and a variable. In addition to the description a generative analysis is developed whereby the relative clause is treated as the structural core for the remaining constructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locations and situations: Negation and finiteness in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/locations-and-situations-avar-negation-tindag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/locations-and-situations-avar-negation-tindag/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I discuss a number of restrictions on sentential negation marking in Avar, a Northeast Caucasian language, and sketch a tentative analysis of the observed morphosyntactic facts as having a semantic basis. The two different negation markers (-ro and -č&amp;rsquo;o) are analysed, based on the proposal in Ramchand &amp;amp; Svenonius 2014, as taking complements of a different syntactic size and semantic type.
In particular, I show that the two negation markers attested in Avar differ in the type of semantic object they can compose with: for the present and future tenses -ro combines with a Fin*P denoting a set of propositions, whereas past-tense negation utilises the biclausal predicational strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a non-cartographic approach to Avar focus movement</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2013/avar-focus-goettingen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2013/avar-focus-goettingen/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I examine the Avar focus construction, restricting my attention to situations where focus marking brings with it a change in the morphosyntactic appearance of the verb. I argue against the popular cartographic approach to focus whereby non-syntactic, interpretative information is instantiated as a head in the functional structure of the clause, and pursue an alternative, free-merge based approach to focus movement.
Superseded by chapter 5 of my PhD thesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matrix constituent interrogatives in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2012/avar-wh-questions-istanbul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2012/avar-wh-questions-istanbul/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I examine two strategies of posing a matrix wh-question in Avar, restricting my attention to situations where focus marking brings with it a change in the morphosyntactic appearance of the verb. I argue against the popular wh-extraction approach, and analyse the two strategies as involving clefting.
Superseded by chapter 4 of my PhD thesis.
Keywords: syntax, semantics, wh-questions, Avar
This is a peer-reviewed talk at Typology, theory: Caucasus, a conference co-hosted by Boğazici University and the French Research Institute in Istanbul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the coreference rule: Reflexivity in Russian Sign Language</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/breaking-coreference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/breaking-coreference/</guid>
      <description>This paper is concerned with the distribution of reflexive and non-reflexive pronouns in local anaphoric configurations in (three dialects of) Russian Sign Language (RSL). We demonstrate that most of the observed facts can be accounted for on a Binding Theory supplemented by a version of the Coreference Rule (Büring 2005). We also show that an additional mechanism, coreference via the signing space, is required to explain certain cases of non-complementarity. A related mechanism is proposed to account for similar facts in spoken languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Рефлексивы в дагестанских языках и природа анафорических отношений</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/refleksivy-v-dagestanskix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/refleksivy-v-dagestanskix/</guid>
      <description>In this paper I discuss the data from North-East Caucasian languages from the perspective of current views on the syntax and semantics of anaphora.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Turkish _kendisi_ is a pronominal</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/why-kendisi-is-a-pronominal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/why-kendisi-is-a-pronominal/</guid>
      <description>This paper is concerned with the syntax and semantics of the Turkish pronominal element kendisi ‘self.3SG’ that has so far received very little attention in the literature on anaphoric relations. We start out by examining the properties of this pronoun proceeding next to discuss the few existing proposals highlighting their inadequacies when confronted with novel data. We argue that despite its reflexive root, kendisi should be treated as a pronominal for the purposes of the Binding Theory, and should be sensitive to Condition B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax and semantics of constituent interrogatives in Standard Avar: a base-generation approach.</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/avar-wh-questions-woss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/avar-wh-questions-woss/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I examine two strategies of posing a matrix wh-question in Avar, restricting my attention to situations where focus marking brings with it a change in the morphosyntactic appearance of the verb. I argue against the popular wh-extraction approach, and analyse the two strategies as involving clefting.
Superseded by chapter 4 of my PhD thesis.
Keywords: syntax, semantics, wh-questions, Avar
This is a peer-reviewed talk at the 8th Workshop on Syntax and Semantics, a conference co-hosted by CNRS and Université Paris 8 in Paris.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wh-fronting is not (necessarily) wh-movement</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/avar-wh-questions-infl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/avar-wh-questions-infl/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I examine two strategies of posing a matrix wh-question in Avar, restricting my attention to situations where focus marking brings with it a change in the morphosyntactic appearance of the verb. I argue against the popular wh-extraction approach, and analyse the two strategies as involving clefting.
Superseded by chapter 4 of my PhD thesis.
Keywords: syntax, semantics, wh-questions, Avar
This is a talk at the final workshop of the Irish Network in Formal Linguistics held at Dublin City University](http://dcu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long distance anaphora in Avar: Why it can’t be empathy all alone</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/avar-reflexives-utrecht/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/avar-reflexives-utrecht/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I present a detailed description of the behaviour of various classes of (anaphoric) pronouns in the Northeast Caucasian language Avar. I use these data to argue against approaches to anaphora based on pragmatic notions such as empathy.
Keywords: syntax, semantics, binding theory, reflexives, reciprocals, Avar
This is a talk at the World of Reflexives workshop at Utrecht University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Sign Language Pronouns, Indexicality and the Signing Space</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/rsl-reflexives-utrecht/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/rsl-reflexives-utrecht/</guid>
      <description>(with Vadim Kimmelman)
In this talk we present a detailed description of the behaviour of various classes of (anaphoric) pronouns in three dialects of the Russian Sign Language.
Keywords: syntax, semantics, binding theory, Russian Sign Language
This is a talk at the World of Reflexives workshop at Utrecht University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Hicks, Glyn. 2009. _The derivation of anaphoric relations_. John Benjamins: Amsterdam/Philadelphia</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/osla-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/writing/osla-review/</guid>
      <description>This paper reviews the derivational approach to binding as proposed by Glyn Hicks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantification, possession and the DP/NP debate</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2010/quantification-possession/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2010/quantification-possession/</guid>
      <description>This is an invited talk at the Leiden Syntax Lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Coreference Rule</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2010/coreference-rule-stuttgart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2010/coreference-rule-stuttgart/</guid>
      <description>(with Vadim Kimmelman)
In this talk we present a detailed description of the behaviour of various classes of (anaphoric) pronouns in three dialects of the Russian Sign Language and compare them with the distribution of similar pronouns in Turkish.
Keywords: syntax, semantics, binding theory, Russian Sign Language, Turkish, coreference
This is a peer-reviewed talk at the Peculiar Binding Configurations workshop at the University of Stuttgart.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>