<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Presentations on Pavel Rudnev’s website</title>
    <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Presentations on Pavel Rudnev’s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Anaphor Agreement Effect: An East-Caucasian perspective</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2021/paris-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2021/paris-webinar/</guid>
      <description>The Anaphor Agreement Effect (AAE) is an empirical observation stating that reflexive pronouns tend to fail to trigger non-trivial φ-agreement on the verb (Rizzi 1990, Murugesan 2019, Preminger 2019).
Theoretical approaches to anaphora seeking to reduce reflexive binding to agreement postulate an inherent featural deficiency for referentially dependent expressions (Kratzer 2009, Rooryck &amp;amp; Vanden Wyngaerd 2011, Murugesan 2019). If it is not resolved via Agree during the derivation, the resulting structure either spells out trivial/defaul agreement (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In support of post-syntactic head movement: Loanword accommodation in Kunbarlang verb phrases</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2020/tmp2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2020/tmp2020/</guid>
      <description>(with Ivan Kapitonov)
Since the early 1990s the verb phrase is generally thought to be built from acategorial roots which are categorised via Merge with functional projections, such as v (see e.g. Marantz 1997). One of the questions about this architecture concerns the nature of head movement: is it syntactic (e.g. Travis 1984) or post-syntactic (e.g. Platzack 2013). In this paper we adduce novel data to argue that it cannot be reduced just to the former option (contra e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic locality, split ergativity and adposition agreement in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/iatl-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/iatl-2019/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: In this talk, I develop a configurational approach to case and agreement in the Avar biabsolutive constructions.
This is a peer-reviewed talk, for the 35th annual meeting of the Israel Association for Theoretical Linguistics, at The Open University in Ra&amp;rsquo;anana.
You can view the slides here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic locality, split ergativity and adposition agreement in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/lagb2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/lagb2019/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: In this talk, I develop a configurational approach to case and agreement in the Avar biabsolutive constructions.
This is a peer-reviewed talk, for the 2019 Annual Meeting of the Linguistics Association of Great Britain at Queen Mary University of London.
You can view the slides here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic phases, split ergativity and adposition agreement in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/camcos8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/camcos8/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: In this talk, I develop a configurational approach to case and agreement in the Avar biabsolutive constructions.
This is a peer-reviewed talk, for the 8th installment of Cambridge Comparative Syntax at St John&amp;rsquo;s College, Cambridge.
You can view the slides here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards an exhaustification analysis of plain disjunction in Russian</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/farl3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/farl3/</guid>
      <description>It has been known since at least Szabolcsi 2002 that the Russian plain disjunction marker ili behaves as a positive polarity item (PPI) when occurring under clausemate negation, which manifests itself in a violation of De Morgan’s laws. Among properties which the Russian plain disjunction marker ili shares with conventional PPIs such as some are the locality of anti-licensing and the ability to be rescued by a second negation.
The Russian plain disjunction marker ili displays variable behaviour with respect to PPI-hood when interacting with Ā-movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Against Upwards Agree: A view from Daghestan</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/formlab-agreement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/formlab-agreement/</guid>
      <description>This talk discusses a recent approach to ϕ-agreement as formulated in Bjorkman &amp;amp; Zeijlstra to appear. According to that approach, all probing relations are established by probing “upwards”, and all exceptions traditionally analysed as involving probing “downwards” are viewed as being parasitic on such Upwards-Agree relations. By looking at (ϕ)-agreement patterns in two morphologically ergative East-Caucasian languages, Mehweb and Avar, I identify what I view as insurmountable empirical hurdles to Bjorkman &amp;amp; Zeijlstra&amp;rsquo;s analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Features in Minimalist syntax</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/formlab-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2019/formlab-features/</guid>
      <description>This talks provides an overview of approaches to featural dependencies in current minimalist work starting from Chomsky (1995). I also discuss aspects of the theory of feature structure which, though often taken for granted, present non-trivial challenges to developing explanatory analyses of featural dependencies. In addition to ϕ-features, the features I discuss are as follows:
 interpretable vs. uninterpretable valued vs. unvalued second-order features/EPP-features features-of-features ([E]-features) formal wh-features formal information-structural features   I conclude, in broad agreement with Šimík (2012) and Boeckx (2015), that the only domain where postulating formal features does not lead to problems are morphosyntactic agreement phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agreeing adpositions in Avar and theories of Agree</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/agreeing-adpositions-in-avar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/agreeing-adpositions-in-avar/</guid>
      <description>Given the central spot afforded to unvalued features in current minimalist theorizing, the directionality of feature valuation is the subject of a lively debate in the syntactic literature. The traditional conception of upward valuation, whereby the unvalued probe inherits features from a valued goal in its c-command domain (Chomsky 2000, 2001, Carstens &amp;amp; Diercks 2013, Preminger 2013), has to compete with downward valuation (Zeijlstra 2012), Hybrid Agree (Bjorkman &amp;amp; Zeijlstra to appear), bidirectional Agree (Baker 2008), amongst others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>East Caucasian coordination</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/east-caucasian-disjunction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/east-caucasian-disjunction/</guid>
      <description>This talk discusses East Caucasian coordination strategies from the viewpoint of recent decompositional approaches to “logical” vocabulary (words like and, or, not etc.) as pursued by Mitrović (2014). Focusing on the predictions of that analysis concerning the unavoidability of exclusivity inferences in the case of reduplicated pairs of μ- and κ-particles, I identify a disjunction strategy in Avar that casts doubt on the universality of the analysis and suggest possible workarounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimalism: Linguistic theory and considerations of simplicity</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/hse-spb-minimalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/hse-spb-minimalism/</guid>
      <description>This is an invited guest lecture for Misha Knyazev&amp;rsquo;s undergraduate course on theoretical approaches in linguistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plain disjunction markers in Russian and positive polarity</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/sle-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2018/sle-2018/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: We know since at least Szabolcsi (2002) that disjunction markers in certain languages display remarkable similarities with some in English, similarities attributable to both groups of elements’ status as positive polarity items. In the case of disjunction, this translates into the inability of disjunction to scope under a local sentential negation leading to violations of De Morgan’s laws: He doesn’t speak Russian or German in Russian can under certain circumstances be interpreted as a disjunction of negations, the narrow scope reading being unavailable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The nature of restrictions on the expression of negation in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/on-the-nature-of-restrictions-on-avar-negation-ras/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/on-the-nature-of-restrictions-on-avar-negation-ras/</guid>
      <description>I have recently presented my ongoing work on the syntactico-semantic properties of negation in Avar in the Andic seminar at the Institute of Linguistics of the Russian Academy of Sciences. This was my first Russian-language presentation after a long lull.
In the talk, I argued that the rather idiosyncratic morphosyntactic properties of Avar negation, as well as the restrictions on the expression and interpretation of negation, can be accounted for in a framework postulating an ontological distinction between (sets of) events and (sets of) situations as conceptual underpinnings of the hierarchy of functional projections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disjunct size, positive polarity and the scope of disjunction in Russian</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/disjunct-size-iatl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/disjunct-size-iatl/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: In this talk I show that the positive-polarity status of the plain disjunction marker ili ‘or’ in Russian correlates with the phrasal vs. clausal nature of disjunction. In particular, I demonstrate that appealing to the availability of phrasal disjunction can shed some light on the hitherto unobserved obviations of anti-licensing effects characteristic of PPI-disjunction markers in a variety of languages (Szabolcsi 2002 et seq.).
This is a peer-reviewed talk, for the 33rd annual meeting of the Israel Association for Theoretical Linguistics, in Tel-Aviv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paths to positive polarity: PPI-disjunctions in Russian</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/paths-to-positive-polarity-farl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2017/paths-to-positive-polarity-farl/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: We know since at least Szabolcsi (2002) that disjunction markers in certain languages display remarkable similarities with some in English, similarities attributable to both groups of elements’ status as positive polarity items. In the case of disjunction, this translates into the inability of disjunction to scope under a local sentential negation leading to violations of De Morgan’s laws: He doesn’t speak Russian or German in Russian can under certain circumstances be interpreted as a disjunction of negations, the narrow scope reading being unavailable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The syntactic side of positive polarity: PPI-disjunctions in Russian</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/syntactic-side-of-positive-polarity-leiden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/syntactic-side-of-positive-polarity-leiden/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: We know since at least Szabolcsi (2002) that disjunction markers in certain languages display remarkable similarities with some in English, similarities attributable to both groups of elements’ status as positive polarity items. In the case of disjunction, this translates into the inability of disjunction to scope under a local sentential negation leading to violations of De Morgan’s laws: He doesn’t speak Russian or German in Russian can under certain circumstances be interpreted as a disjunction of negations, the narrow scope reading being unavailable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Particles, disjunctions and inquisitivity in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/disjunction-concessivity-avar-tabudag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/disjunction-concessivity-avar-tabudag/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: This paper discusses a previously neglected disjunction strategy in Avar (NE Caucasian), whereby each disjunct is accompanied by a morphologically complex disjunction marker =nigi yet the disjunction is not interpreted exclusively, unlike the reduplicated discontinuous disjunctions like soit_soit in French.
The disjunction marker is exponentially identical with the particle attaching to indefinites and turning them into polarity items: šib=nigi ‘what=POL (ie someting/nothing)’ as well as the marker of concessivity that attaches to verbs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Core and peripheral disjunction strategies in Russian: Their interaction with sentential negation</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/core-and-peripheral-disjunction-tindag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2016/core-and-peripheral-disjunction-tindag/</guid>
      <description>This paper’s point of departure is the generalisation in Szabolcsi (2002) that natural languages differ in the way that their disjunction markers can be interpreted when embedded under negation.
(1) Mary doesn’t speak German or Polish.
= Mary doesn’t speak German and she doesn’t speak Polish.
Corresponding sentences in Hungarian are interpreted exclusively: either Mary doesn’t speak German or she doesn’t speak Polish (Szabolcsi 2002). Szabolcsi (2002) proposes that the contrast between English and Hungarian lies in the status of Hungarian ‘or’ as a positive polarity item, in contrast to English or.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The interaction of disjunction and negation in Russian</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/disjunction-negation-in-russian-syntaxif/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/disjunction-negation-in-russian-syntaxif/</guid>
      <description>The project takes as its point of departure the generalisation found in Szabolcsi (2002), which has become a standard reference point in the literature on negation and disjunction, that natural languages differ in the way that their disjunction markers can be interpreted when embedded under negation. Examples (1) and (2) illustrate the contrast.
(1) Mary didn’t take hockey or algebra. = ‘Mary took neither hockey nor algebra.’ 
In languages like English the most salient interpretation of (1) is that Mary took neither hockey nor algebra, whereas it is seldom interpreted as saying that Mary didn’t take either of hockey or algebra together but that she may very well have taken one of them but not the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A study of Avar negation</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/avar-negation-groningen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/avar-negation-groningen/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I discuss a number of restrictions on sentential negation marking in Avar, a Northeast Caucasian language, and sketch a tentative analysis of the observed morphosyntactic facts as having a semantic basis. The two different negation markers (-ro and -č&amp;rsquo;o) are analysed, based on the proposal in Ramchand &amp;amp; Svenonius 2014, as taking complements of a different syntactic size and semantic type.
In particular, I show that the two negation markers attested in Avar differ in the type of semantic object they can compose with: for the present and future tenses -ro combines with a Fin*P denoting a set of propositions, whereas past-tense negation utilises the biclausal predicational strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locations and situations: Negation and finiteness in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/locations-and-situations-avar-negation-tindag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2015/locations-and-situations-avar-negation-tindag/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I discuss a number of restrictions on sentential negation marking in Avar, a Northeast Caucasian language, and sketch a tentative analysis of the observed morphosyntactic facts as having a semantic basis. The two different negation markers (-ro and -č&amp;rsquo;o) are analysed, based on the proposal in Ramchand &amp;amp; Svenonius 2014, as taking complements of a different syntactic size and semantic type.
In particular, I show that the two negation markers attested in Avar differ in the type of semantic object they can compose with: for the present and future tenses -ro combines with a Fin*P denoting a set of propositions, whereas past-tense negation utilises the biclausal predicational strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a non-cartographic approach to Avar focus movement</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2013/avar-focus-goettingen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2013/avar-focus-goettingen/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I examine the Avar focus construction, restricting my attention to situations where focus marking brings with it a change in the morphosyntactic appearance of the verb. I argue against the popular cartographic approach to focus whereby non-syntactic, interpretative information is instantiated as a head in the functional structure of the clause, and pursue an alternative, free-merge based approach to focus movement.
Superseded by chapter 5 of my PhD thesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matrix constituent interrogatives in Avar</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2012/avar-wh-questions-istanbul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2012/avar-wh-questions-istanbul/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I examine two strategies of posing a matrix wh-question in Avar, restricting my attention to situations where focus marking brings with it a change in the morphosyntactic appearance of the verb. I argue against the popular wh-extraction approach, and analyse the two strategies as involving clefting.
Superseded by chapter 4 of my PhD thesis.
Keywords: syntax, semantics, wh-questions, Avar
This is a peer-reviewed talk at Typology, theory: Caucasus, a conference co-hosted by Boğazici University and the French Research Institute in Istanbul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax and semantics of constituent interrogatives in Standard Avar: a base-generation approach.</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/avar-wh-questions-woss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/avar-wh-questions-woss/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I examine two strategies of posing a matrix wh-question in Avar, restricting my attention to situations where focus marking brings with it a change in the morphosyntactic appearance of the verb. I argue against the popular wh-extraction approach, and analyse the two strategies as involving clefting.
Superseded by chapter 4 of my PhD thesis.
Keywords: syntax, semantics, wh-questions, Avar
This is a peer-reviewed talk at the 8th Workshop on Syntax and Semantics, a conference co-hosted by CNRS and Université Paris 8 in Paris.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wh-fronting is not (necessarily) wh-movement</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/avar-wh-questions-infl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/avar-wh-questions-infl/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I examine two strategies of posing a matrix wh-question in Avar, restricting my attention to situations where focus marking brings with it a change in the morphosyntactic appearance of the verb. I argue against the popular wh-extraction approach, and analyse the two strategies as involving clefting.
Superseded by chapter 4 of my PhD thesis.
Keywords: syntax, semantics, wh-questions, Avar
This is a talk at the final workshop of the Irish Network in Formal Linguistics held at Dublin City University](http://dcu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long distance anaphora in Avar: Why it can’t be empathy all alone</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/avar-reflexives-utrecht/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/avar-reflexives-utrecht/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I present a detailed description of the behaviour of various classes of (anaphoric) pronouns in the Northeast Caucasian language Avar. I use these data to argue against approaches to anaphora based on pragmatic notions such as empathy.
Keywords: syntax, semantics, binding theory, reflexives, reciprocals, Avar
This is a talk at the World of Reflexives workshop at Utrecht University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Sign Language Pronouns, Indexicality and the Signing Space</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/rsl-reflexives-utrecht/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2011/rsl-reflexives-utrecht/</guid>
      <description>(with Vadim Kimmelman)
In this talk we present a detailed description of the behaviour of various classes of (anaphoric) pronouns in three dialects of the Russian Sign Language.
Keywords: syntax, semantics, binding theory, Russian Sign Language
This is a talk at the World of Reflexives workshop at Utrecht University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantification, possession and the DP/NP debate</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2010/quantification-possession/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2010/quantification-possession/</guid>
      <description>This is an invited talk at the Leiden Syntax Lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Coreference Rule</title>
      <link>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2010/coreference-rule-stuttgart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavelrudnev.github.io/presentation/2010/coreference-rule-stuttgart/</guid>
      <description>(with Vadim Kimmelman)
In this talk we present a detailed description of the behaviour of various classes of (anaphoric) pronouns in three dialects of the Russian Sign Language and compare them with the distribution of similar pronouns in Turkish.
Keywords: syntax, semantics, binding theory, Russian Sign Language, Turkish, coreference
This is a peer-reviewed talk at the Peculiar Binding Configurations workshop at the University of Stuttgart.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>